my objective with this video is to teach
you three very important parts of
trading number one is an effective
strategy that utilizes moving averages
and Candlestick patterns to point out
High likelihood zones in the market for
trading opportunities number two is to
teach you exactly how to place live
trades with a real account on the
trading view platform and number three
is to teach you a very underutilized
tactic for controlling your emotions and
for mastering your trading mindset so if
that sounds good go ahead and click that
like button for me go ahead and
subscribe if you are new and I'll be
right back after the intro and display
foreign
[Music]
welcome back and just in case you're
brand new my name is Steven I've been
trading for about a decade and I am the
founder and trading coach here at TTC
let's get started by talking about this
effective strategy that utilizes moving
averages as well as Candlestick patterns
in a bit of structure in order to point
out accurate trading opportunities so on
the screen you can see that we have a
moving average here that's that red line
you see this moving average specifically
is the 20 EMA now when it comes to
moving averages that I use for things
like areas of value I use the 20 EMA the
50 EMA and the 200 EMA those are the
only three moving averages that I use
for support and resistance what I also
refer to as areas of value now this is a
trade I'm about to place live with you
here but I want to do this analysis and
breakdown first before we actually place
the trade so let's take a look at what
we have we have prices currently doing
what when we were in an uptrend and
hopefully at this point you can see this
reversal this reversal is what I call a
one two three move we have price making
an impulsive move down followed by a
smaller pullback slash lower high from
our previous High we then have another
lower low with this impulsive move this
signifies the start of a bearish trend
or a possible bearish Trend which is
what we're trying to capture so with
this strategy we're looking for this
move this one two three reversal then
waiting for price to pull back to a
specific moving average in this case the
20 EMA and we have a couple of other
things that we're going to be looking
for as well but the first thing we need
to see is this one two three reversal
move a reversal and Trend now to the
bearish direction next we have this
pullback now coming up to this moving
average do you see anything else that we
could utilize to add accuracy to a
possible trading opportunity in this
situation
hopefully you were able to look left and
say yes we have a decent level of
structure looking left we have this
level of support that's been tested
multiple times as resistance and support
and what I like to do with this specific
strategy is add a level of support like
this or a level of resistance a level of
structure in general like this that's
been tested multiple times
with a specific moving average again I
use the 20 50 or 200. so in this case we
had this level of structure lining up
very closely with our 20 EMA now if
you've been a part of the channel you've
heard me talk about cesd a million times
c s c e s d is an acronym I use to
create trading opportunities and trading
strategies everything we've discussed so
far would fall into the category of
conditions now what do we need after
conditions in order to have a
rules-based way of trading we're going
to need a reason for entry then your
stops and your targets that's what the
whole acronym stands for so at this
point we have our conditions met of
price creating this lower low reversal
move we have a pullback to the moving
average which is the 20 EMA which aligns
with a major level of structure looking
left so what can we look for for
possible entries well some of my
favorites to use are Candlestick
patterns so if I zoom in here you'll see
why I'm about to place this trade I'm
literally about to go short ear again I
want to do that live with you so I can
show you how to place trades on a live
account in the trading view platform but
here if we zoom in a little closer we
actually have a really nice Candlestick
pattern we have a rejection right here
this otherwise known as a shooting star
candle comes up this is buyers trying to
take control throughout this entire Wick
but when price hits this area of
structure combined with our 20 EMA what
happens
sellers say no sellers create this long
Wick now that's good but waiting for
some added confirmation can make things
a little more accurate so what happens
next next we get a large or large
comparison to the previous candle at
least in terms of the body a large red
candle so this is what I need to place a
trade at this point the conditions we've
already discussed have been met my entry
is right here with our long Wicked
candle followed by a red Candle In the
Zone remember that has to happen after
the conditions are met so with this
being the case this is how I would like
to place this trade I would go ahead and
enter there which I'm about to enter I
have to take it off Market replay mode
and actually enter the trade which I'll
do again in just a second I'm going to
check out the ATR which is what I use to
play stop losses the ATR of this candle
is right up here it's right at 45 Pips
right now by the way with the ATR you
discount the last number so that is 0.45
or 45 Pips 45 Pips on the ATR which
means I'm gonna go about 40 to 45 Pips
above the high of this wig to have a
safe stop loss so that's going to be
about 91 Pips which gets me above my
major level I'm going to look for about
a 1.4 to 1 reward your risk ratio which
is the reward to risk that I personally
like to use a lot of the time once price
gets to
this little level here I will probably
move my stop loss to break even if we do
push down we may go straight up and hit
my stop loss I have no idea but this
trade is giving me a positive expectancy
because of all the things we've already
discussed all the conditions coming
together along with these Candlestick
patterns gives me a positive expectancy
so with that being the case let's go
ahead and remove Market replay so I can
place this trade live with you and if
you haven't noticed what did we
accomplish by going through this entire
trading process we accomplished c e s t
a completely rules-based way of trading
and rules based strategy so let's go
take out a live trade here on the Euro
again getting out of Market replay mode
oh no a big green candle now for a lot
of new or struggling Traders you may
think that I'm sitting here going no I'm
definitely not going to enter this trade
now because this big green candle quite
the opposite what this big green candle
tells me is I'm getting a better entry I
can have a smaller stop loss and a
larger reward to risk ratio all of my
analysis even though there's a green
candle right here that's pushing higher
all of my analysis is still valid I
still have my major level of structure
lining up with the 20 EMA I still have
the Candlestick patterns that existed
before this one so I don't have any
reason to expect this trade not to win
at this moment so because of that I'm
going to go ahead and set up a new
position tool
with a stop loss at the same spot and a
Target at the same spot and now I'm
getting closer to a 2.4 to 1 reward your
risk ratio based on the same trade just
because I'm getting in one candle later
at a higher price so let's go ahead and
place this trade so that you guys can
see it done live the first thing you
have to do is set up a brokerage with
trading view if you do not see your
brokerage whenever you open up the
trading panel that just means that your
brokerage is not able to connect with
trading view if that's the case either
find a new brokerage or just place the
trade in your own trading platform
whenever you want to trade but for me my
brokerage is a Wanda so I'm gonna go
ahead and connect to that
to avoid thousands of people seeing my
account information I did fast forward
through that but as you can see down
here we are on a live account this is
one of our smaller accounts but I am in
fact going to go ahead and place this
trade so first off before I place a
trade I always use this position tool
that trading view has and just in case
you don't know where that is I have it
favorited but you can just go right here
it's under whatever this is called
prediction and measurement tools and
once you click that you can find short
position and long position I favorite
them but I have that position tool on
the chart every single time I place a
trade and the reason is it makes placing
a trade so easy at this point all I have
to do is right click the position tool
after putting the entry where I want it
putting the stop loss where I want it
and putting the target where I want it
after I have that done all I have to do
is right click click create limit order
and then go to market order at the point
or or limit whatever you want to place
right Market limit or stop I'm going to
be placing a market order I'm going to
be using about a two percent risk here
and this is literally the entire process
of placing a trade at this point all I
have to do is Click sell
I'm involved in the trade that is the
entire process of placing a trade in
trading View and exactly how you do it
and in my opinion if you have a broker
that connects to trading view this is by
far the easiest way to place trades and
especially if you use a certain percent
of your account as your risk management
plan so now with that out of the way
we'll see how this trade plays out it's
currently Friday so if you want to check
this chart maybe it's Saturday Sunday or
next week by the time you see this or
years down the road who knows but feel
free to check it I obviously have no
idea if it's going to win or lose and
I'm okay with it either way because of
my good risk management that I have set
up of a two percent loss on this
specific trade with that out of the way
though let's go take a look at a bullish
version of this strategy then we'll talk
about that underutilized way to master
your trading mindset here we are on the
pound twist we're gonna take a look at a
bullish version of this strategy by the
way if I sound nasally in my voice
cracks it's only because I'm currently
battling strep throat I honestly think
the only way I'm going to get rid of it
is if you smash that like button for me
totally joking you don't have to do that
hopefully the antibiotics will work but
if you've made it this far in the video
you might as well so let's take a look
at a bullish version of this what do we
have Happening Here on the pound Swiss
now I will admit in this case we do not
quite have a one two three move but what
we do have is a large impulsive move
breaking above the previous level of
resistance this will suffice for a trade
for me if we get that we get a large
impulsive move breaking above a level of
resistance I count that as a possible
reversal what do I mean by that what I
mean by that is at this point if we get
a pullback that touches our 20 EMA and
coincides with this previous level of
structure that's been tested multiple
times then I can look for possible entry
opportunities so let's see what price
does after pointing out our structure
level so this would be the area that I
would be interested in a trading
opportunity from based on the conditions
of this strategy so let's see what price
does okay we're inside the zone and
we're pushing off of the 20 EMA and we
do have a good Candlestick pattern here
but again I like to see more
confirmation than this so I would be
waiting on a green candle after a long
Wicked candle in order to get involved
next up we have another red candle that
is also still a hammer candle still a
long whip to the bottom side showing
buying pressure but not a green candle I
need to see a green candle for
confirmation and there we go finally we
get a green candle there so the way this
position would look is something like
this I would take the ATR of this candle
which is currently 58 Pips so let's go
58 add that to the bottom of this week
which means we have about 113 Pips for
this stop loss and again I like to go
for about a 1.4 to 1 reward to risk
ratio so at this point if we're looking
at this at c e s t we have our
conditions met of moving average area of
value combined with our area of
structure we have our entry met with a
long Wicked candle followed by buying
pressure for a bullish trade we have our
stop in place and our Target in place
this is where I would actually place the
trade if I click play you'll see that
price did eventually push up high enough
to hit our Target anything I tell you
about trading psychology will be
completely useless unless you have
mastered what I'm about to tell you if
you have not mastered the basics of
whatever Market you're trading in if you
have not mastered either technical
analysis or fundamental analysis or both
whatever you decide to trade based on
and if you have not mastered creating a
strategy that's rules based enough for
you to stick to and proven to be
profitable over time along with mastered
risk management then I can speak for
hours about trading psychology and it
will help you zero because until you've
mastered those four things nothing I say
about trading psychology is going to
help you in any way shape or form so if
you are currently at the position where
you you don't have a Mastery level
understanding of the basics of the
market you're trading in or you haven't
mastered technical slash fundamental
analysis or both and you don't have a
strategy that's rules based that you're
sticking to and you don't have a risk
management plan then you need to work on
all of that and then come back to
learning about trading psychology feel
free to stick around through this lesson
but understand that nothing about
trading psychology is going to be
applicable until you master those other
four parts of your training
after you have those things mastered
trading psychology and discipline can
still be a bit difficult and this is
where this little hack comes into play
so many Traders see themselves as bad or
inadequate based on the results of a
single trade or a single week you may go
out and lose two or three trades in a
row and think of yourself as inadequate
as a Trader think of yourself as a as a
loser in the markets for lack of better
terms and think about this whenever you
last joined a signal service if you ever
have
what if they sent you two signals in a
row and they were both losing trades
have you ever gotten that and been like
oh this guy absolutely sucks at trading
obviously he doesn't win he just lost
two trades in a row if you have don't
worry you're not alone when I was
starting out that's what I thought too
when in reality that person may be a
good Trader but they just had two losses
in a row they may not be a good Trader I
know some signal services are a bit
sketchy but the point here is no matter
how skilled you become no one will ever
know what the Market's going to do at a
specific moment no matter how much skill
you acquire at trading you're not going
to know what price is going to do on one
specific trade as I learned from Mark
Douglas our ability to be profitable
relies on our ability to understand and
accept that we are trading based on a
statistic advantage that plays out over
a large sample size of Trades so
although we can't predict exactly what
the Market's going to do with a hundred
percent accuracy right now we can make a
very high likelihood assumption based on
a large sample size of Trades and a
predictable pattern that is proven to be
profitable over time otherwise known as
a strategy so to make this very clear as
a professional Trader I am not trading
based on what I know the Market's going
to do next
I am trading based on a statistic
advantage that plays out over a large
number of Trades you will be trading
when you are profitable not based on
what you know the market will do no
matter how skilled you are you will
never know what the market will do at
that exact moment but what you will be
trading based on when you become
profitable is a statistic advantage that
plays out over a large sample size and
for me that sample size is about 100
trades so what I do is I pay attention
to my trading based on a sample size of
100 trades I don't look at it going oh I
lost two trades today oh I had four
losses in a row oh I didn't make money
this week or oh I didn't make money this
month I look at it as over the past 100
trades have I had an edge over the
market in back testing that's how I back
test in real trading that's how I trade
and that's how I'm able to have a good
trading mindset throughout drawdowns and
even throughout losing streaks is by
accepting and knowing that I'm trading
not based on me knowing what the
Market's going to do no I don't have a
crystal ball my name's not Merlin
there's no way for me to know exactly
what price is going to do and there's no
way for anyone to we are trading the
based on a statistic advantage that
plays out over a long period of time and
by the way I am currently looking for
500 new or struggling traders to mentor
and help accomplish their trading goals
throughout the remainder of this year so
if you're looking for some more advanced
training and you want access to a full
University style course that'll walk you
through the entire process of building
your own trading plan using strategies
and techniques that have been profitable
for me over the years along with email
analysis which is alerts I send you two
to five times a week the Pro Trader
report every Monday which are the areas
of structure I'm paying attention to for
trades and priority coaching support
which means you have access to me
anytime you have questions it's a full
mentorship program then go ahead and
click that top Link in the description
or go to
www.thetradingchannel.com and if that's
not something you're interested in no
worries at all just make sure you're
subscribed here make sure you click that
like button if you made it to the end go
ahead and comment below I wish you the
best of luck on all your future trades
and I'll see you in the next next video
talk soon